Lucas Cavalcanti Rodrigues

Data Engineer

Links

Github Linkedin Stackoverflow

Technical Skills

OS

GNU/Linux, Windows

LANGUAGES

Python, Javascript, Rust, R

FRAMEWORK

flask, node.js, pandas, matplotlib, statsmodel, scikitlearn, sympy

DATABASES MySQL

CLOUD

GCP

OTHERS Markdown, Git, Vim, VS Code, Jira

Analytical Skills

Data Structures
Algorithm
Probability
Data Analysis
Econometrics
Machine Learning
Agile methodologies

Education

2017-2021 PHD ECONOMICS Universidade de São Paulo

2013-2014 MR. SC. IN ECONOMICS Universidade Federal de Juiz de Fora

2009-2012
B.A. IN ECONOMICS
Universidade Federal
de Juiz de Fora

Bom Retiro · São Paulo - SP lucas.ecomg@gmail.com +55(11) 95600-2307 30 years

Summary

I'm a Data Engineer with experience in data analysis, statistics, and working in dynamic teams. My technical knowledge includes scripting languages, databases, and cloud computing. I'm also a highly motivated professional, with strong organizational and multi-tasking skills, who always aims to add value to the business and the teams I work with.

Experience

CURRENT

Data Engineer

DP6

I work on collecting and structuring data obtained from customer interaction channels such as mobile apps and websites

Python, Javascript, Google Analytics, Firebase, GTM

2020-2021 **Economist**

Parceiros da Educação

I was responsible for creating the ESG Racial Equity Index (IEER), a metric used by several companies in the Brazilian private sector to assess and monitor the status of racial inequality among their employees. In addition to develop the index, a by-product of my doctoral thesis, I was also responsible for the data infrastructure used to compute the index. The infrastructure was built using resources from the Google Cloud Platform (GCP).

Python, Pandas, GCP, Cloud Storage, Big Query, Flask

2016-2017 Data Analyst

CAED

The Center for Public Policy and Education Assessment is an institution responsible for the external assessment of the educational systems of Brazilian states and municipalities. I contributed to public policy reports directed to the subnationals Departments of Education by carrying out the statistical analysis of microdata. In these analyses, among other techniques, I used statistical methods such as Factor Analysis, Index Construction and Linear Hierarchical Models.

SPSS, Microsoft Office

Other Employment

2016-2017 Professor of Economics

UFJF

2021-2021 Data Consultant

MPT

Certifications

Google Analytics Individual Qualification TOEFL ITP

Issued Aug. 2021

Issued Feb. 2019